♪ ♪
Hey... hey,
hey... hey!
Hey, let her go!
Hey!
Thank you.
Are you all right?
Yeah, I think so.
You sure?
Yeah.
Brian, you took
a big risk for me.
I really owe you.
Please, i-it was nothing.
What do you mean?
I don't know what I would have
done if you hadn't come along.
Excuse me.
Sure.
Hello.
Oh, Jason, hi.
Yeah.
Are you kidding?
That much?
Wow, that's great.
Yeah, sure.
Count me in, okay.
Thanks, Jason, you're the best.
Well, my day is looking up.
Was that your boyfriend?
Former, but we're
still good friends.
He's an investment broker.
After we split up, he
offered to invest for me,
and I've been
making a lot of money.
You want some more coffee?
Uh, no, no.
Oh, I've really got
to get back to work.
Oh, me, too.
Uh, listen...
Thanks for the coffee.
Brian, thank you.
You're welcome.
Uh, yeah...
I'll see you later.
Come in.
Brian?
Madeline.
I'm interrupting.
No, no, n-no.
C-Come, come on in.
I didn't think I'd
ever see you again.
How are you?
Well... I couldn't be better.
What's this?
I told you I invest
in the market.
I added a few dollars for you,
and the stock went up 22 points.
They announced a
merger yesterday morning.
You knew?
Me? No, I don't know a
merger from a takeover.
It's enough that Jason knows.
He... knows about mergers
before they happen?
Mm-hmm.
Madeline, your friend's
involved in insider trading.
Well, I don't know that.
All right, maybe I do know it,
but the important thing is that
every time he invests my money,
he doubles or triples it.
You ever lose?
Huh, once.
Would he do it for me?
Well, I don't know,
I could call him,
but I don't want you
to risk your own money.
Taking a risk is how I met you.
You have a problem.
What?
What is it?
It's very serious.
Wha-What are you talking about?
How are you going
to spend $2,500
of pure profit?
You're kidding.
You're wonderful.
Not only that...
I'm rich, richer than
I was yesterday.
$9,000.
Ooh... that friend of
yours... Edmunds...
He knows what he's doing.
Has he... got anything else?
I don't want to call him again.
You know you could lose.
Accountants know that.
Well... there's going to
be another major takeover
in the next few days.
Hmm.
Jason says the stocks
could jump 20 to 30 points.
I want in.
Well, why not?
I could get together $25,000.
Hmm?
I'll go to the bank
tomorrow morning,
get the money, meet
you here at noon.
Sounds like a plan.
Takes care of tomorrow, huh?
What about tonight?
That's up to you.
Well, that's strange.
Where's the receptionist Tina?
Well, maybe she's at lunch.
Come on.
Jason, it's me, Maddy.
Jason.
That's odd; he knew
we were coming.
Oh, my God. What is it?
It's Jason.
Somebody called the police.
We got to get out of here.
We can't leave
him here. Madeline,
insider trading is illegal.
You want the police
to come in here,
find you standing over Jason's
body with $75,000 in cash?
Come on, let's go.
Okay...
Come on, the stairs.
Here, let me have that.
What are you doing?
The police are outside.
We'll come back for it tonight.
All right... We'll meet
at my place later.
Where the hell is she?
I told you
I'm not going in; I told
you I want to see Jason.
- Get out of the car.
I'll do it later.
Get your stuff. I
want to see him now.
I'm not getting out, so
why don't you just drive?
Let's go.
Well, I told you
I'd meet you later.
But, baby, I wanted to see you.
I told her to get her
stuff out of the apartment
before she came here,
but she couldn't wait.
Lay off her, Jack.
Maddy knows what's important.
We are good together, aren't we?
Classic, the best.
You gave him a little thrill or
two, didn't you, Maddy, hmm?
It was only business,
baby, you know that.
Please.
Save it for the motel.
Come on, let's get on with this.
Okay, here's $25,000, right?
Less $3,000 for the mark,
$1,000 for the boys.
That leaves 21.
That's seven apiece for us.
God, he was easy.
Okay, pay attention.
Tomorrow afternoon,
Yvonne, between 3:30 and 4:00,
I'm going to bring
the mark here.
You conned me.
Yeah, we did.
You took me for $25,000.
I want it back.
You invested it with someone
you thought was an inside trader.
Shame on you, Davis.
Huh, what would
your clients think?
Remember them...
The people who trust
you to handle their money?
You can't cheat an
honest man, Davis.
There are six
thieves at this table.
I'm gonna get you, Edmunds,
I'm gonna get all of you.
I don't know how, I don't know
when, but this isn't over yet.
I-I've never done anything
illegal in my life, you know.
Forget it.
Think of all the money
you're going to make.
Yeah, well, that's why I'm here.
Jason.
He's probably on the phone.
Huh.
Uh, maybe we
should wait outside.
No, no, he's probably just
stepped out for a minute.
Jason.
Oh, no.
Come on, we've
got to get out of here.
Yeah, right.
Gotta be cops outside.
What if they see
this? Dump it, dump it.
They'll be coming
for it. Dump it, dump it!
Forget this. Ah!
What the hell are you doing?!
Give me that briefcase!
You want it? Call the police.
This doesn't square
things, Maddy.
This is only a down payment.
Jason, get up! We blew it.
Jason?
Jason!
Get me the police!
Didn't it seem odd
that you were taking
cash to a stockbroker?
Sure.
But I kept making money.
But your father left
you plenty of money.
Well... I made out the will.
Ben, it wasn't so
much the money.
I know, I know.
A good-looking woman.
Easy money.
Just enough risk to
increase your heartbeat.
Exciting, wasn't it?
They suckered me, Ben.
But I didn't kill Edmunds.
I hope not.
Unfortunately, security
adjacent Edmunds' building
has you on tape entering
that building at 2:30.
That's an hour and a half
before Madeline saw
you in the stairwell.
Where were you for 90 minutes?
I was waiting.
They said they'd be there
between 3:00 and 4:00.
Here's something
else you're gonna like.
Madeline Medford has
turned state's evidence.
She's been given full
immunity for her testimony,
and she's a believer.
What?
She believes you
killed Jason Edmunds.
Who's gonna believe
a con artist anyway?
If she's good, everybody.
All right, we're covered.
Hi.
Well, Bob, you find anything?
No. Hi, Ben. Afraid not.
Uh, victim was stabbed.
Looked like he was sitting
in his chair when it happened.
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
Boy.
He spent a lot of money.
Hmph. Eh, not really.
Um, there's lot of
empty cubicles out there.
Fax machine doesn't work.
It's all show.
Computer works.
It's plugged in, that's all.
It's not piped into
the Dow Jones.
What's all this?
Well, your stock symbols.
I guess Edmunds
wanted to make it look like
he was following some stock.
Yeah.
Uh, excuse me.
What can I get you? Yeah.
Uh, I'm looking for
a Jack McCarthy.
Don't know him.
I'm told he
frequents this place.
Don't know him.
It's okay.
I was expecting Mr. Matlock.
Oh!
It's a nice suit.
Oh, thanks.
So, how's the
investigation going?
Oh, thanks.
Well, it's not easy.
There's too many
people with motives.
Dozens of them
all over the country
madder than hell at
you and your colleagues.
Well, what do you expect?
I mean, we're con men after all.
You act like you're proud of it.
I do what I do.
And I'm very good at it.
The way I hear it,
you and Miss Medford have
worked together for years.
Maybe you figured
you could do it better
without Jason Edmunds.
Uh, a three-way split is harder
than a two-way.
No, no, I don't kill people.
Oh, you don't? No,
I don't believe
in it, first of all.
Secondly, you know,
there's some states...
You kill someone, they
catch you, they kill you.
I mean, where's the
percentage in that?
Yeah.
Oh, where were you, um,
before you showed up
at Mr. Edmunds' office?
With my mark... Kenneth Roberts.
For two hours.
Honest.
♪ ♪
Hi. Hey.
Do you know anyone in
here who owns a blue Lincoln?
Nope.
What about it?
Oh, I hit it.
It's just a small dent, but I
wanted to alert the owner.
Wait a second.
Yeah, well, could be worse.
No, Mr. McCarthy,
I can't believe I did this.
How's your car?
Not a scratch.
Look, if it's all
the same with you,
I'd rather keep my
insurance company out of this.
Look, um...
why don't you buy me a drink?
We'll call it even, huh?
Miss Medford, I appreciate
you're seeing me.
Just so you know,
I don't like turning
state's evidence.
It's just that the
DA\ convinced me
I wouldn't like prison.
Yeah, well, that's true.
Um...
I understand you and
Jason Edmunds were close.
Very close.
I'm sorry, this must
be a bad time for you.
You know what you can do
with your sympathy, Mr. Matlock?
Wrap it up and send
it to the federal prison,
where your client will
be serving a life sentence.
I'm gonna get up on that
stand and I'm gonna bury him!
Miss Medford, you-you amaze me.
You make a business
out of breaking the law,
and then get mad when you
think somebody else might have.
If you've got a handbook
with your code of ethics,
I'd like to read it.
Yes.
We have a very
firm code of ethics.
We don't kill anybody.
Um, the coroner has established
the, uh, time of death
as being between 2:00 and 3:00.
I don't suppose you
were in Mr. Edmunds office
between 2:00 and 3:00?
It was more like 4:00.
You can ask the police
what time I called them.
And for three hours before that,
I was at the Eighth Street bar.
You can ask half a dozen people.
I'll see you in
court, Mr. Matlock.
So, we'll have dinner
tomorrow night, huh?
Last call, everybody. Last call.
No, I'm not having
dinner with you.
Yeah, of course, you're
having dinner with me.
I already made reservations.
Well, you're sure of
yourself, aren't you?
Well, you owe me.
Banged up my car.
I'll pay the damage.
Forget it. That's not why
you're having dinner with me.
You're gonna have dinner
with me because you want to.
Don't you?
You know this McCarthy
is very, kind of, um...
Well... Captivating?
Yeah. In a way.
Well, he's a con man.
He has to be captivating.
He won't get the work.
Not getting the work's
hard on a person.
Even a con man?
Yeah, I guess so.
Did you find out
anything about him?
No. Nothing.
Phone's unlisted.
And the company said
they never registered a
telephone to a Jack McCarthy.
Hmm. An alias maybe.
Oh, yeah.
Well, how about a
home address? Nope.
Mr. Roberts?
Uh, Mr. Roberts?
Uh, I'm Ben Matlock.
This is Michelle Thomas.
Uh, we'd like to ask you some
questions about Jack McCarthy.
This is private property.
I-I want you to leave.
We just want to talk,
Mr. Roberts, that's all.
I didn't do anything illegal.
Nobody's accusing
you of anything.
Uh, we represent Brian Davis.
Maybe you read about
him in the newspaper.
And we just... we
need your help!
I... I'm sorry.
Oh.
I...
You must think
I'm pretty stupid.
You're not the first
person to fall for that con.
I knew it was wrong.
I never had a shot
at easy money before.
It didn't seem like it
was hurting anyone.
Jack McCarthy said
that you and he were together
for more than two hours
before you visited,
uh, Jason Edmunds.
Yeah, I think so.
Except when I went to
the bank to get the money.
McCarthy didn't go with you?
No.
No, we met back here
before we went
over to the office.
How long were you here alone?
I don't know.
Uh, half hour.
Maybe 45 minutes.
Oh. Has to be.
Jack McCarthy. Yeah.
♪ ♪
I cannot take my eyes off you.
Mm.
That's a beautiful ring.
Is it?
Yes.
Where'd you get it?
I took it from a
mark in Seattle.
You stole it?
Oh, no, no, it's
nothing like that.
You take something
personal from a mark,
it's like owning a piece of him.
Just part of the
game, that's all.
Huh.
You make it sound so harmless.
Oh, no, it's not harmless.
Nothing in life is harmless.
Anybody...
at any time can
turn against you.
Life's one long
surprise, Michelle,
as you're finding out tonight.
What do you mean?
Well, you're here, aren't you?
I mean, you know this is wrong.
And here you are.
If you're like me,
you don't want
this night to end.
We'll have coffee at your place?
I have a houseguest.
That's what I said.
We'll have coffee at my place.
So...
I've got a, uh, 40-year-old
bottle of brandy.
Been saving for a
very special occasion.
You can tell me if it
lives up to its reputation.
Did you steal it?
No.
I bought it.
I've got to go home.
Michelle.
No. Stop it.
You know you want to.
You know that.
What does wanting
have to do with anything?
No, I'm not like you.
I can't just take
whatever I want.
Shh, shh, shh.
No.
Look... I'm a lawyer.
I work with Ben Matlock.
Yeah? So what?
I know that.
How do you know that?
It's not important.
I know that.
Why didn't you say
something before?
Because you would leave.
The game would be over.
I want you to take me home.
Evening. With the gas company.
Are you... Jack McCarthy?
No, McCarthy's next door.
I'm his landlord.
He isn't home.
Oh. That's okay.
You can help me.
I'm gonna have to check
Mr. McCarthy's premises,
so I guess if you'll
accompany me...
What's the problem?
Well... we have a
report of a gas leak.
A leak? What kind of leak?
Well, actually, we don't know.
Could be extensive,
but we'll have to
check it out and see.
You mean the
house could blow up?
We at the gas company
prefer not to think negatively, sir.
Helen, get out here.
We're going for ice cream.
Thank you.
Helen? Now!
Having a good time?
Mmm.
Yeah.
I got hungry.
Got so hungry, I couldn't think.
How about you?
Uh, no.
I'm not that hungry.
No, I mean, you're
having a good time?
Oh, I'm having a great time.
I just had this huge
plate of waffles
smothered in fresh peaches,
served up by this
sweet thing named Mary.
Investigation's going great.
What did you find out? Well,
our friend McCarthy...
He makes his bed,
he reads Elmore Leonard
and eats takeout Chinese.
That's all? Yeah.
Except for, according
to his phone bill,
he calls San Francisco
every Wednesday at 6:00 p.m.
Hmm?
What do you think about that?
I think that's a long ways
to call for Chinese takeout.
What was your job
in this particular con?
Well, my job is to
retrieve the briefcase
after they've left the building.
Did you do that?
I tried to, but
when I got there,
Brian Davis was holding it.
And what happened next?
I tried to take it from
him, but I couldn't.
He was very angry, and, uh,
I was afraid he might kill me.
Object.
Move to strike. JUDGE
COOKSEY: Sustained.
The witness's last remark
will be stricken from the record.
Miss Medford, you will
refrain from speculating
on the, uh, state of
mind of the defendant.
Do you remember what he said?
Yes. He said
that taking the briefcase
didn't square anything.
It was only a down payment.
No further questions.
Cross-examine, Mr. Matlock?
No questions.
You may step down.
Call your next witness.
Prosecution rests, Your Honor.
Mr. Matlock, call
your first witness.
Uh, defense calls Jack
McCarthy to the stand.
Mr. McCarthy,
would you say
that you and Jason
Edmunds were, uh, close?
I'm not sure I
understand the question.
Did he know your real name?
McCarthy is my name.
Well, yeah, now it is.
But how about,
uh, up in San Francisco
where you were arrested
for a series of crimes?
Uh, weren't you known as
Leonard Mathis?
Objection, Your Honor.
No relevance.
Improper impeachment.
Mr. Matlock, you
should know better.
Rephrase the question.
Objection sustained.
Yes, sir.
Isn't it true that in the
San Francisco area,
you were known
as Leonard Mathis?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Do you know a
Sergeant Edward Higgins
of the San Francisco
Police Department?
I can't say that I do.
That's very odd.
Sergeant Higgins says
that, uh, you call him
every Wednesday at 6:00.
That is the deal you made
with the San Francisco
Police Department, isn't it?
Well, I guess I can't dispute
both you and Sergeant Higgins.
Well, well, good.
Good, good.
How about this?
Uh, Jason Edmunds
found out your real identity,
and threatened to turn
you in to the Atlanta police
unless you gave him
most of your share
of the con games the
three of you were pulling.
No, Jason couldn't do that.
'Cause you were...
you were best friends?
Friend?
Jason would sell his mother.
No, Jason couldn't blackmail me
because the Atlanta police
already know who I am.
I'm famous.
Uh, according...
to the coroner's testimony,
uh, Mr. Edmunds was
killed between 2:00 and 3:00.
And you showed up at his office
with Mr. Roberts around 4:00.
Where were you
between 2:00 and 4:00?
With Mr. Roberts
for the entire time.
You were never out
of each other's sight?
Never at all.
Hmm.
Uh...
You know, since...
Since I got
involved in this case,
I've-I've, uh... I've
done a lot of reading
about the confidence game.
And there is a...
a universal language
among con men.
Have you ever heard
the expression "the send?"
Yeah, I've heard
that expression.
Would you tell
them what it means?
The send is when you
send the mark to the bank
to pick up the money
to invest in the scam.
And when did you
send Mr. Roberts?
Mr. McCarthy,
Mr. Roberts
is prepared to testify
that between 2:00 and 2:45
the day of the murder,
you sent him to the bank
to get the cash for your
phony investment deal.
For 45 minutes, you
were out of his sight.
Where did you go?
Mr. McCarthy, you have no alibi
for the time of the murder.
I have to believe
that you killed Jason Edmunds.
You want an alibi, huh?
Okay.
During that 45-minute period,
I was in the office
of the venerable police
sergeant Harold Marks.
You're a police informer?
It's a deal I made
with the D.A.'s office.
They would pretend that
San Francisco never happened
if, in return, I would
keep them posted
on the activities of
various underground figures
that they were interested in.
I think you just
cost me that job.
And that's where you were
for that 45 minutes?
At the Atlanta
Police Department?
How's that for an alibi?
The best.
Cross-examine?
No questions, Your Honor.
You may step down.
Due to the lateness of the hour,
this court will stand in recess
until 10:00 Monday morning.
Court is adjourned.
Conning the police.
I didn't think he had an alibi,
and the damn thing
jumped up and bit me.
Yeah, what-what do we do now?
I'm damned if I know.
No.
Sergeant Marks said
you're willing to help me.
Yeah, well, he didn't exactly
give me much choice, did he?
I guess I am your
mark, Mr. Matlock.
Look at these.
Yeah.
It's Jason looking very dead.
You notice anything,
uh, unusual?
Even a small thing?
It's my business, Mr. Matlock,
to notice unusual things.
Maybe even
especially small things.
Are you talking
about this pale line
here around his wrist?
Yeah.
He had a pocket watch.
What was he
wearing on his wrist?
It's an I.D. bracelet.
His own, or did he
steal it from somebody?
Oh.
Well, I wouldn't
know that, would I?
This was taken
from the computer screen
in Jason Edmund's office.
It's supposed to be a
list of stock symbols,
and they all are.
Except for this last one.
Any idea what that might be?
Beats me.
Whatever it is, it
has to do with the con
that you and Jason
Edmunds were pulling.
I haven't a clue.
Somebody's initials, maybe?
Thanks.
You've been a world of help.
Anytime, Mr. Matlock.
After all, I am here to serve.
Now, Mr. Roberts, uh,
you're fairly new to
Atlanta, aren't you?
Yes, sir.
I moved here about
three months ago.
Where from?
Denver, Colorado. Oh.
That's a pretty big change...
From Denver to Atlanta.
Now, what prompted the move?
You ever spend a
winter in Denver?
Up there, these old bones
never thawed out until August.
So, uh...
so, you're here permanently.
Oh, you bet.
You know, from what I hear,
you didn't buy a home here.
You're renting.
A nice little two-bedroom
on Morgan Street.
And your furniture's
rented, and so is your car.
Everything about
your life is-is, uh...
uh, temporary, disposable.
It's hard to believe that
you plan to stay in Atlanta.
Man my age has to be careful.
I didn't want to invest
a lot of money here,
in case things didn't work out.
I can understand that.
Uh, do you remember the day
you met, uh, Jack McCarthy?
I'm afraid so.
Uh, where was it?
It was in Arrowhead Park.
I was jogging.
His car broke down,
and I gave him a lift.
Well, that's neighborly of you.
I never was able to turn down
somebody who was in trouble.
Yeah, but what about this?
What if you drove up
there to find Jack McCarthy?
You knew who he was, didn't you?
What?
Well, that's not true.
I believe you knew Jack
McCarthy was a con man,
and you deliberately
set yourself up
to be taken by him,
didn't you, Mr. Roberts?
Well, why would I do that?
For two reasons.
One, to get, uh,
Jason Edmunds...
That's the man you were after...
And two, to give
yourself a perfect alibi.
Objection.
No foundation.
Assumes facts
not in evidence yet.
Your Honor, give
me three minutes,
and I'll lay the foundation
and place the facts in evidence.
Three minutes, Mr. Matlock.
Objection overruled.
Thank you.
Now, the police believe that
you were an innocent victim.
And, when you told
me about the 45 minutes
that you and, uh, Jack
McCarthy were apart,
I immediately focused
on Jack McCarthy.
You knew I would, didn't you?
I was just answering
your question.
But, you know, then
it occurred to me...
If, during that 45 minutes,
you couldn't see Jack McCarthy,
he couldn't see you, either.
You conned the
con man, didn't you?
Your Honor.
Two minutes and
counting, Mr. Matlock.
Time flies, Your Honor.
On the day of the murder,
you went to the bank
and withdrew $20,000
to give to Jack McCarthy.
Right? That's right.
You went to the bank,
withdrew the money on
the day of the murder?
Yes. Okay.
Now, I'm showing
you this document,
which we subpoenaed from the
Atlanta Crestmore National Bank,
and ask if you recognize it.
Yeah, that's my bank statement.
It shows the $20,000 withdrawal.
Yeah, it shows the
$20,000 withdrawal,
but not on the
day of the murder.
See, look right here.
The money was
withdrawn on March 17,
the day before the murder.
That must be a mistake.
In-in Jason Edmunds' office,
there's a computer
monitor with a lot of symbols
and-and-and initials on it.
And it, uh... this... this
is a computer printout
of those symbols.
And, uh, would you just
tell us what they mean?
Well, they're New York
Stock Exchange symbols.
That's... that's why I
knew he was legitimate.
Right, right.
Look here right at the bottom.
See that part?
See these initials?
PMR.
See that?
Uh, you... you... your...
your son's name, uh...
Peter.
Peter...
Michael Roberts.
PMR. No, no, no.
No, that's... that's
just a coincidence.
Mr. Roberts...
how is your son?
He passed away.
No, sir.
He committed suicide, didn't he?
He committed suicide
because he had lost
thousands of dollars
to a con man... Jason Edmunds.
Your son's death
broke your heart,
and you lived for revenge.
You went to Jason Edmunds
when Jack McCarthy
thought you were at the bank.
Maybe Mr. Edmunds
asked who you were,
what, uh... what
he could do for you.
Maybe you told him
something about your son.
Anyway, you introduced yourself
as Peter Roberts'
father, and you killed him.
No.
I wasn't at the
office at that time.
I didn't go there.
Mr. Roberts...
this is the police photograph
of the murder scene.
Now, at first, nothing
seems unusual,
but if you look
at his right wrist,
there's a little white line
around his wrist there,
like he had worn, you
know, a wristwatch.
But the police say
that Mr. Edmunds
carried a pocket watch.
What do you suppose caused
that white line on his wrist?
Oh, how would I know?
Well, Jack McCarthy tells me
that con men like to
steal something personal
off of people they've conned.
Doesn't matter why.
They just do it.
And, uh, Mr. McCarthy
and I spent a...
good bit of time talking,
and he is now willing to testify
that Jason Edmunds
took something
personal off your son.
A gold I.D. bracelet.
And on the back was inscribed,
"You have made me so proud."
Then, the word, "Dad."
Mr. Roberts, I noticed
that you're wearing,
uh, an I.D. bracelet.
Would you mind taking it off?
Mr. Roberts, I
appreciate how you feel,
but I must see the bracelet.
Those con men
swindled him out of everything.
Savings.
House.
Car.
He was so ashamed,
he... he couldn't tell me.
I found out when I...
when I read the letter that
was lying next to his body!
Those people are scum.
They don't just...
prey on people.
They... they destroy them.
Nothing further.
Michelle.
Since I'm a, uh...
police informer now, having
turned state's evidence,
I'm going to have
to give up the con.
For a while.
Go straight, I guess.
But I, uh...
For starters, I want
you to have this.
Please.
No, I did not steal it.
My father gave it to me.
Brought me luck.
How do I know
you didn't steal it?
I guess you don't.
But you want it.
And so, from now on,
wherever you go, you have a
little piece of Jack McCarthy.
Take care of yourself.
Hungry?
Starved.
Tell you what... you hold this.
You guess which
hand this coin is in,
and I'll buy.
Deal?
Okay.
But you know how
much I eat when I win.
Yeah, we'll see.
We'll see. Ha, ha.
Oh, wait, wait,
wait, wait a second.
What's that?
www.tvsubtitles.net